Daniel Stevens

dan.stevens2@gmail.com

Currently unemployed Reading, United Kingdom

07939 987944

Between March 2012 and December 2019 I had been working as a technical consultant for Oracle Consulting Services, which I became part of through the acquisition of RightNow Technologies in 2012, where I had been a Quality Assurance Engineer and Application Engineer.

Having worked with RightNow CX (now called Oracle Service Cloud) for several years, I've gained a wealth of experience in the field of CX and have been able to contribute to the delivery of solutions to customers in a range of industries from Consumer Electronics to Utilities. I love to code and so my favourite implementations usually involve some form of customisation, such as back-end PHP scripting or C# .NET UI extensions. Recently I've been cultivating a side interest in Javascript based technologies such as Node and React and video game development.

Professional Experience

2012 – 2019 Consulting Services, Oracle Corporation UK Ltd. (via acquisition)

Worked as a Technical Consultant / Cloud Application Engineer specialising in Oracle Service Cloud. Main responsibility is working closely with customers to understand the business needs and requirements and to design and implement solutions to fulfil them.

2008 – 2012 RightNow Technologies

Developers of CRM cloud service named RightNow CX, created to help consumer-centric organisations deliver positive customer experience and interactions to their customers. Acquired by Oracle Corporation in 2011. Worked as a QA Engineer in their Professional Services department, providing testing services for bespoke customisations. Responsibilities included:

- Establish and maintain quality assurance processes.
- Documented test cases for manual, system level testing.
- Assisted with ongoing goal of providing software solutions of excellent quality that met the needs of customers.

Education

2003 - 2007

BSc Computer Science at the University of Wales, Aberystwyth

Four-year sandwich course. Graduated July 2007 with a 2:2 class degree.

Subjects of study: Java & C programming, Operating Systems, Web Development, Program Design, Software Development Life Cycles, Agile Methodologies, Database Management Systems, Internet Architecture.

Technologies

- C# .NET
- PHP, SQL
- HTML, CSS, AJAX, JQuery
- Javascript ECMA 6, Node.js, React
- REST, SOAP
- Windows
- Linux/Unix shell scripting
- GIT SCM
- Windows Powershell

Certifications

Scrum.org Professional Scrum Master I

Project Experience

Two examples of projects I was involved with while working for Oracle Consulting Services.

Sony Interactive Entertainment Europe

Implement a customisation for integrating Sony Playstation Network Account data into Oracle Service Cloud. This involved implementing a REST API in PHP that acted as proxy for Sony's own REST API, and an add-in component implemented in C# .NET that interacted with the REST proxy api.

Prince's Trust

Reworked an Oracle Service Cloud add-in component (implemented in C# .NET) for performing postal address lookup. The result was improved maintainability and scalability of the add-in code, and involved using the Adaptor design pattern and abstract types (interfaces) to reduce code duplication.

Personal life

Prior to lockdown I was taking part in a 6 month Mission Discipleship Training program with Christian missionary organisation *Operation Mobilisation*. Unfortunately, this came to an early end due to the pandemic.

My hobbies include playing guitar. Up until late last year I was the lead performer in a 3-piece covers band. During the lockdown I have taken the opportunity to develop new skills, one of which is recording and producing music at home.

My faith in Christ and being part of the church in Reading is a significant part of my life. It is my faith that led me to become involved in mission. While I'm not able to go overseas at present, I've been helping in my church's local missionary work by volunteering with FoodShare, a service that distributes unsold food to the community.